# HASSAN ABDIRAHMAN

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

#### **EDUCATION**

**University of Birmingham**( 2021 – 2022) Full – Stack Development Course Grade A+

University Of Johannesburg (2012 – 2015)

Bachelor in Management Engineering

#### SKILLS & TECHNOLOGIES

NodeJS	HTML5
Bootstrap	CSS3
MongoDB	NPM
JavaScript	Docker
React	GraphQ
ExpressJS	Tailwind
Typescript	Jquery
Next.js	APIs
Jest	AWS
HTML	

#### <u>ACHIEVEMENTS</u>

- 2019 Cisco Academy NetAcad Member
- 2021 Best Customer Service SysZtream Solutions
  - 2020 Team Project Leader
  - 2020 Brainnest Frontend Industry training.

#### **FUN FACTS**

#### **INTERESTS**

Volunteering · Investing · Football

#### **HOBBIES**

Weightlifting · YouTube · Blogging · Gaming

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

A Full Stack Developer familiar with wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Handles any part of process with ease. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering years of related experience.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Software Developer SYSZTREAM SOLUTIONS LIMITED | Nov2022 - Contract

- Designed reusable and reliable code for use within distributed cloud environments.
- Collaborated with project managers to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones on pre-release software project development.
- Translated basic design plans into full iOS app frameworks, delegating project components to appropriate team members.
- Applied Agile software development methodology to elevate final products and streamline development efforts.

**Skills:** TypeScript, Mongoose ODM, Tailwind CSS React.js, JavaScript, MongoDB, NodeJS

## **Trainee Full Stack Developer**

## University of Birmingham | Nov 2021 - Sept 2022

- Creating the user-facing parts of web applications using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. proficient in front-end frameworks like React.
- Contributed to projects within Scrum project management environments.
- Able to identify and solve complex technical problems to analyze code and debug errors.

**Skills:** HTML5, Tailwind CSS, React.js, JavaScript, CSS, Boostrap, HandlebarsJS, MongoDB, MySQL, NodeJS, GraphQL, JEST, Jquery.

## **IT Support Engineer**

### SPM Computers | Aug 2019 - Aug 2021

- Provided complete end to end engineering and installation of route based IP network solutions.
- Monitored network capacity and performance to diagnose and resolve complex network problems.
- Provided detailed network diagrams and procedural guidelines.

github.com/hassanmahdi58 | Linkedin/in/hassan-abdirahman-18a455175/

REFERENCES

AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST